Eric Dickerson

Singapore

ericdickersonfree@gmail.com



+13473058085



https://www.linkedin.com/in/eric-dickerson-1ab7302ab/

Summary

- Always Open to Remote Job -

An experienced full-stack developer with 6 years of experience specializing in distributed systems and web3 technologies.

Launched several Ethereum and Solana Contracts, created NFTs and provided MVPs.

Following the client's business idea, I 've completed more than 10 projects related to various technical fields

from scratch.

I enjoy solving difficult technologies and I am good at creating technical solutions related to business use

I value honor, integrity, punctuality and teamwork

Passionate about building world class web applications

Also Experienced Frontend developer with a passion for Web and mobile app development.

Recognized for strong problem-solving skills and an ability to quickly learn new technologies.

Eager to join a team of talented developers and help build world-class mobile apps.

Experience



BLOCKCHAIN | FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

Full-Stack Developer, 07/2023-12/2023

Bkwire - [bkwire.com]

- •I redesigned database of bkwire.com site and developed backend on RDBMS using django and PostgreSQL.
- •And I rebuilt user interface using React.js according changed backend and database

Senior Full-Stack Engineer, 11/2022 - 06/2023

Betsmixer-,TX [betsmixer.com]

- Utilized modern web technologies and frameworks to build intuitive and efficient user interfaces, enhancing overall user satisfaction.
- •Led cross-functional teams in implementing full stack solutions, integrating front-end and back-end components for cohesive application functionality.
- •Designed and optimized databases (PostgreSQL) for efficient data storage, retrieval, and management.
- Developed and implemented a web-based application using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and React.js.

Web and Mobile Frontend Developer

Omniverse Lab

May 2022 - Oct 2022 (6 months)

- Developed and maintained React and React Native components, screens, and features for the web and mobile app using TDD practices.
- П
 - Collaborated with other developers to implement new features in a way that is consistent with existing codebase conventions.
 - Provided technical leadership by mentoring junior engineers on best practices related to software development and engineering processes.
 - Participated in design discussions regarding application architecture, feature implementation, or any other relevant topic as required.
 - Assisted in developing test plans for new functionality prior to release and assisted QA team during testing of releases when needed.
 - Developed front-end user interface using React and React Native for Web Interface and iOS and Android mobile applications.
 - Utilized React Native debugging tools such as Reactotron and Remote JS to identify and fix bugs.

BLOCKCHAIN | FULL-STACK DEVELOPER Upwork

Oct 2019 - Apr 2022 (2 years 7 months)

- -Created the NFT minting website / Staking platform / Raffle platform/ Betting platform with Solidity and Rust on Solana and Ethereum network
- build the blockchain using the Golang and implement a basic, backend-based, custom blockchain application in Rust using Substrate
- write operation systems or microcontroller applications using the rust
- -web scraping tool with python, Machine learning tools, website with React.is/

Redux&Vue.js&Angular&Node.js, Java project, Django/Flask server developemnt

- Android/IOS development with Flutter, React Native and Xamarin
- Presale / ICO / IDO / IGO / STO Development

BLOCKCHAIN | FULL- STACK DEVELOPER MagicCraft Ltd

Jan 2021 - Sep 2021 (9 months)

- -Created the ERC20 Token for Game Platform
- -Developed an ERC721 token contract as well as smart contract for democratic voting by token holders
- -Created the NFT Minting and Marketplace website with React/Redux and web3.js and Node.js
- -Demonstrated wallet generation, ether and token transfers, balance ,checks, and listening for events
- -Advised on best security practices
- -Built a backend server for monitoring Binance contracts and creating transactions
- -Discord Bot for Marketing
- -Optimized the smart contract code and increased the efficiency by 15%, using the Library functionalities of the solidity



Full-stack Developer

Mazama

May 2019 - Dec 2020 (1 year 8 months)

- -Created the Al Chat bot for Facebook messenger
- -Interface development with Html, CSS, JavaScript, React, Angular, Typescript

-Backend development with Node.js, Django , Django Restful framework -NLP and NLU for AI using the Rasa



Full-stack Developer Kisko Products

Mar 2018 - Jan 2019 (11 months)

Developed a sports polling website (betpolls.com) that provides users with the betting odds on each game and a user-friendly voting system, and supports fantasy sports games.

Developed a back-end API using Node.js, PHP, Lumen, and MySQL.

Created a web admin portal with React, Redux, and Shopify Polaris and a front-end portal with Laravel Blade templates and Bootstrap.

Implemented various search engine optimization techniques using Google Tag Manager and Ahrefs as SEO tools.

Education



National University of Singapore Bachelor's degree, Computer Engineering

Apr 2013 - Sep 2017

Skills

React.js • Node.js • React Native • Rust (Programming Language) • Python (Programming Language) · Java · AngularJS · Vue.js · Solidity · PHP